what's going on YouTube
this is I'm doing sauna from hack the box
which is just a
windows box with a web server and active directory
and start on it
we've done plenty of 80 in the past
the videos that come to mine
a real active sizzle and forest
the thing that really sets this one apart
is you can't just use
RPC client or L DAP to dump all the users on the box
instead we can kind of
do a boolean logic to check if a user exist
through kirbros pre authentication
essentially you give it a username if
kirbros responds with
pre authentication required
you know that user exist on the box
so we're going to go through the website of the box
pull a bunch of names off the site
and then use a bit of them
magic to convert those names into possible usernames
pass it into a tool called curb route
to find some valid usernames
and then with those usernames
pass it to some impacket scripts to do some as
rep roasting to get a
password hash of an account pass it to hashcat
crack it log into the box
and then once you log into the box
privasking is simply running
blood hound and wind peas
combining the 2 outputs and you can DC sync
so it probably sounds a lot more complicated than it is
so let's just jump in
as always we want to start over
the n map so dash s C for default scripts
s V enumerate versions O a I'll put all formats
print the n map directory and we have to create it
create the n map directory
and then we can call it sauna
1010 175
always want to run and map with pseudo
and then I'm gonna add a dash V flag
so we can see open ports as it finds it
we see 80 is open which is going to be a web server
53 DNS a bunch of um like SMB RPC ports
I don't know exactly what 3268 is
um don't know what five ninety three
I think 06:36 is encrypted L DAP
we see kerbros down here
so based upon saying 4 45 which is SMB
so we know there's a windows box
53 DNS and 88 kurbrose
I'm guessing this is a windows domain controller
so the very 1st thing I want to do is probably
enumerate 4 or 4 or 5
and then we'll move on to port 80
so let's do
crack map exec SMB 1010
175 to see
everything about this
hurst we see the hurst name is going to be sana
the domain name is egotistical dashbank dot local
signing is set to true and smbv1 is disabled
so
let's do shares to see if we can enumerate any shares
and we get a status use a chess and delete in
we can try a blank username password
to see if this gets around that
sometimes it does sometimes it doesn't
and we see access denied so we can't
we could try other tools like SMB map
I think it's dash I 10 1010 one 75 dash U dash
P
dash H
run
this and we don't really get anything
so
good go and try a bunch of SMB tools
but if crack map exact and SMB map don't get anything
gently move on
we can try RPC client 10 1010 one semi 5
and we can't connect
let's just do a blank user
it's dash capital W
and then I think it's enume dumb users
to see if you can get a username dump
we get access denied so
can't really do anything with this
the one thing I want to do is
start creating notes
so let's do control n to create a new node
call it sauna
control shift n for a child node
call it notes
and then I'm going to
copy the domain egotistical dashbank dot local
and we'll paste that in here
and we can go check out the web server
10 1010 dot one 75
so it looks like a
standard page I'm gonna press ctrl you
and we're gonna see if we can identify what
like CMS or how this is built
if we saw like word press or triple stuff
we note are on those type of scanners
but I don't really
see any of that
the next thing we could probably do
is try to guess the extension
so probably index dot HTML
we got that we could try PHP
not found
ASP
aspx so it looks like it's HTML files
if we did have this in burp suite
we could probably just have burp crawlette and then
identify files that way
so let's turn intercept off
refresh the page
go over to a target
and then we could just look at files this way
and could also
maybe passively scan
ah scan
it's been so long since I used the new version of
Brooks we don't even know how to launch a crawl
but
go through and see if we see any um
extensions but everything is just HTML
so
click on the pages see if we have anything unique
just looking for ways we can interact with this
so there is this newsletter here
so we can put our email address
so do like oh my god is that
so the color is white on white for some reason
so we're just gonna put
please subscribe at ipsec dot rocks
highlight so you can see it
click subscribe and
http verb used to
not allowed
so let's go to proxy intercept
I'm guessing this was a post request
and maybe post just isn't allowed
so send we get method not allowed
this is verb it's like get post head
options there's a few of those verbs
so let's change the request method to a get request
and doesn't look like anything happened
so I'm looking at the paid bytes at the bottom so 31223
just being sure that doesn't change
and let's get rid of this email
so 3 1 2 2 33 1 2 23
so I don't have to read this whole thing
I can guess the page is probably the same
so doing that just did nothing
so we can just move on from that
let's see
let's go all the way up
click around blogs
blogs could have something useful
single
HTML
are these all the same
yes it is
so this is definitely some type of static website
so
this looks like different post
clicking on these post we go to the same
single dot PHP page
so at this point I'm assuming this is just a
static page and we have to just
get some type of valuable information off this
we could run cool
which is like
going to gather a wordless based upon the web page
I bet if we just do anything here
it's going to go to invalid verb
invalid verb so nothing there so
could run cool
and grab information off this
but if we had a password list
we don't really know
an account yet
so
let's see if we can find usernames on a page
so maybe the about us page
and we have
users
so let's copy this
curve with a Cherry Tree
control shift and users
paste doesn't want to paste
so let's windows key L to put down the left oh god
it pasted all the images and everything
but windows key
out
left they put it on the left
I did windows key right here to put it on the right
and it'll just make it quicker to copy and paste
so let's just copy the use names
this way
oh god
control a delete paste
copy paste
copy paste copy paste
so now we have a list of potential users
we have to convert this into
use name formats that windows generally uses so
let's
do this user text
and we could also try searching L DAP
because actor directory does expose LD app
so we can do LD app search
dash X dash H 1010 10 one 75
we have to get the
naming context or dash s base naming context
and we want this string
we can do dashby
and query elder manually and if we're lucky
we could potentially get usernames
but it looks like we don't have
that permission
if we had if I was allowed for anonymous elda
down here you'd see a bunch more information
for like huger smith which is a user I believe
we'd see something like this right here
what is this
this is
DN
let's just grip dash I for sam
because the username
and actor directory is like a sam account name
but we don't get that so
this doesn't really tell us the username format
how odaps not giving us anything
so going back to that users dot text file
we could create a python script to transform this
into a bunch of potential usernames
but whenever you do
like a CTF for you under a time constraint
you don't always want to read a script
and sometimes it's handy just to know how to
use the tools you have
so I'm going to use a vim macro
so we're going to start the macro off by doing Q a
and that means record this macro
and is going to be on a
so I'm going to start this macro off with y
y to yank the line
and I want to change this into probably 3 other things
so I'm going to do a 3
p to put the line I just yanked
3 times so we can see fergusmith is now
got 4
I'm gonna hit home just to my cursors
always gonna be at the beginning
slash space
then s period escape
so that fix that one spot and go hit the down arrow
home key again
write one DW for delete word
go down one hit the home key
right one DWI for insert period to put a dot there
hit the down key hit the home
escape to exit insert mode
and
Q to exit recording mode
so now when I do at a
it replays all those keys I just did to them
and then we have
4 more lines so I can do 4 at a to repeat it 4 times
and now we have a
really nice user list of everything we saw
so w Q to exit
and I'm going to go grab a tool curd called
curb route which 0 xdf pointed out to me
because this does a kubros pre authentication attack
against it 80
and this can help us identify valid users
so essentially
when you attempt to authenticate
to an ad server via cubros
if you have a valid username it's going to say hey
please continue with pre authentication
if you don't have a valid username it doesn't do that
and that's how this attack essentially works
and then you can also do um
root forcing passwords with this
and the cool thing about it
it's not going to create event code 46 24
it's going to create a curbrose failure
thing which by default is not logged
so it's a good way to brute force accounts with
potentially just not being seen
it does increase the
failed login if they have that locked out
you can lock counts without with this
it's not a bypass to that it's just a way to
do a password spray without cleaning that
event code 46 24
but we're not gonna do a password spray with it
we're going to um
use it to
enumerate valid usernames
so I'm just going to download it
you could
clone it and build it yourself if you wanted to
and I'm going to copy that
into my directory
ch mod plus x
and I'm just going to
rename it because I don't want that
Linux MD 64
but when we execute it we can see all the modes
what you want to do user innume
so we do user anom
h
and see the flags
so use a name word list is gonna be users dot text
but before you give it the word list
we have to tell it where the domain controller is
so dash dash d C
1010 175 dash d which is the domain
egotisticalbank dot local
and then now we can do user text
and we don't find a single one
so let's go into user text and let's create something
that we know exist
like an user called administrator
we could also do guest
because these are default windows accounts
so we should get always get hits with these accounts
so we can see
our curb route script does work
because we validate administrator
egotisticalbank dot local exist
so let's see if we want to do
any more permutations on the name
and right now I'm noticing that
there's a space at the end of every line
the dollar sign just means end of line
the space means well it's a space
so let's do colon percent s space dollar sign
and that's gonna search for anything that has a space
and then end of line
do another slash
so replace it with nothing and G to make it global
so now we removed the trailing space from all the lines
let's go and run this again
and we get 2 valid users administrator and F smith
so let's go to users
and we can say
administrator
F smith so we know those 2 are valid
and at this point I'm gonna check
the impacket scripts what we can do with usernames
and to find my location of impacket
I always just do locate PS xx.py
because I never can remember this example directory
but
I highly recommend if you don't know all these scripts
go through each of them
and just like add exact H less
and read the
description to find out exactly what they do
because there's 2 scripts that are super valuable
let's get NP user
which is going to be the
as rep roast or some people call it curb roasting
but this is the as rep one
and it queries the target to main
for users that do not require
curb roast pre authentication set
and it can
export their ticket granting ticket for cracking
and another good one is get user SPN
I think this one set if it's um
store pass when reversible format
I'm not exactly sure what that one is
but definitely take a look at all the impact scripts
there's definitely really good ones there
but this is the one we want to use probably
so let's do
target so this will be egotistical
bank dot local
slash
administrator and the next one we'll do is F smith
and let's see do we get anything
it's taking a while so I'm just going to do 2
egotistical bank dot local F smith
and it doesn't look like it's working oh
we probably should
at this point
add the domain to our DNS
so pseudovi Etsy host
10 1010 one 75 egotistical bank
we can call it also sana and sana dot egotistical bank
so now we say we cannot authenticate to administrator
can't do TGT user administrator doesn't have that set
so now let's try
F smith
and
we can get the
TGT
and we can crack this
because the
encryption key or signing key for this is going to be
the user's password
so let's go over to a crack and machine
and you can just use hashcat on your desktop
I wouldn't recommend using hashcat in a VM ever
just because
cracking is generally a CPU a GPU intensive process
so doing it in a VM where you are constrained
generally doesn't work out well
so VI
let's do hashes slash sauna
paste that and we can do dot slash hash cat
dash dash example hashes
grep for
what was it caroby
or just grep for as rep and look for 23
as rep
so we have it here it's only one format
so I can do less as rap
let me see
mode
18 200
so let's do dot slash hash cat dash m 18200
and the word list which is going
the hashbile which is going to be hashes sauna
and then the word list we want to use 1st
I always use opt word list rock u dot text
and we'll see if we get any hits
we got one crack
looking at it the password is the strokes 23
so let's go here cruds
where was it F smith
the strokes 23
so now let's see what we can use with this
so I'm going to do
crack map exact SMB
10 1010 once MB5
U f smith dash P
the strokes 23
and we can see
it is valid
but it doesn't have pone to it so we can't just
PS exec into it
I'm gonna do dash dash shares
to see if there's any shares
we want to go enumerate
this should tell us if we have right access to anything
and just list them in general
and I guess
okay
I was gonna say that's looks like it's taking a while
um
we do have a printer
that's funny we can print money
oh we can't print money
but
ah
can copy this
notes
paste that
switch point
Rico
some reason remember being
yeah a local privasque with this
where does the state
such point dash X
let's go back to this page
let's do a W get on this image
exhibit tool
on about that HTML
so about that HTML was created February 10th
which is probably around the time this box was created
and the Rico privasque we saw was a 2019 CBE
so I'm just going to
local privasque put a note for that
because that is definitely interesting
but we still don't have a way to get shell in the box
so let's go and try
win RM
for windows are moot
and this will tell us if we can get on the box
come on
sometimes it takes a water run
let's see
and it shows that we can indeed get on the box
so evil win RM I think we give it dash I for IP
10 1010 one semi 5 dash U for user F smith
beef password the strokes 23
and
here we are
so let's go and run win peas
so let's go LS opt
privilege escalation script awesome sweet win peas
when p's exe
it's under think windpiece again
bin
release
win pzxi
let's just
copy that
to a current directory
and then we can upload
win pz dot EXE
to upload this flower to the box
and now we can run it so dot slash win PS dot EXE
and let that run
and while that runs I'm going to go check out Rico
privasque
so let's see
components
and printer setup
so maybe we should run
this command
so it's abusing a create file
and there's a proof of concept
so we should probably try this
let's see
copy this
and
evil when
RM
let's get a 2nd shell to this
so we can run that eye cackles command
to see if the vulnerable driver is on this box
that was not the command I want to run
still not let's do control shift insert
there we go
can I find the path
CD backslash program data
dir
I don't think it exists
should have a Rico driver
and we don't
so
don't know what that's doing there could just be a
something the
creator I think egotistical
wanted to do and then decided not to
so let's just move on
and notes
we can say the directory does not exist
does not exist
so
let's go take a look
and everything let's just go to the very top
there we go
see what it shows so we got power shell 2.0
so we could probably evade
any type of logging if there was
by just going to that
lapse is not installed w digest not enabled
so for nothing is sticking out
no a v USC
and we have auto log on credentials
with
SVC loan manager in this password
so let's go
create creds
SVC loan manager
put this password
and I'm just going to go quickly
seeing if I see anything
like an red highlight yellow
font
because that would mean definitely should look at that
and we don't see anything
so let's do net user
svc underscore loan mgr
slash domain
and so tell us like what groups it's in
and what it is
so it's in remote management user
and it's just a domain user
we can try our account which is F smith
same thing we can do net user domain
and there is a H myth account
so let's just look at what H myth is member of
just the main users doesn't have that remote management
so even we had his password
can't really do anything
this password expires
all right it's already expired
let's check loan manager
how is that configured
password expires never
so let's go and run bloodhound
and I don't think I've ran bloodhound
since I switched to pair it
so the reason why I'm going bloodhound
is because it is active directory so
yeah
gonna install bloodhound 1st with pseudo app to install
bloodhound
yes and then we're going to get
search
Google get hub bloodhound
to quickly go to the bloodhound page
because this is the best place I found
to download the ingestors
if you don't want to compile it yourself
so we can download show pound exe
and doesn't look like wanted to download
what if I can just copy the link
w get
that
sweet downloaded
file shirt pound
come on
time was lagging a little bit
it is a
executable
so I can go back to a shell
upload shut pound dot EXE
and then while that runs we can launch bloodhound
if I need to run this oh
if I don't have to run this one with pseudo
neo for J we're gonna have to start
so pseudo neo for J console
let this start
and then we have to change the password in bolt
so let's go here
then use the name
the default password is also near for J
so let's just put the password of please sub
and now when we go to bloodhound
put the password please sub
we should be able to log in
there we go
bloodhounds kind of picky sometimes when you type
it doesn't try to reconnect
and if it doesn't get a valid connection
doesn't want you click that log on button
if you ever forget the near for j password
I believe
you just delete the
file in here let's see
less
comp
data
databases
see
reset near for J password
near for J
start
I guess you can just follow those
there was normally a file I normally just deleted
and I can't find that file
but
password is please sub
I'm sure the next video
I'm going to have to find a way to
reset the password because almost likely forget it
so we upload a sharp pound we can execute sharp pound
and this will create a zip
and use the
these collection methods group sessions trust ACL
so let's do
download
this file
then we need to go places home to open up
a
file browser
go to sauna
and then we can just drag and drop
on a bloodhound
and we can see
it is now processing
and the 1st thing I always like doing
is marking my user that I have as owned
so I just search for svc loan
Mark user as owned
and we want to Mark F smith
as owned as well
then we can do
see click here
queries shorteth past from owned principles
and let's just check each one
this is just showing we can PS remote to the DC
not showing anything else
so let's check the F smith principle
same exact thing
find all domain admins
only administrator
short as path
let's see enterprise admins were not in that group
administrator is not in that group
and this user
so nothing here helps principles with DC sync rights
oh god let's
weird graph but let's go over this administrator
nothing this is the box itself
we got this one SVC loan manager
so we can click on the edge right click help
and says the user
SVC loan manager has the
DS replication get changes all privilege on the domain
individually the edge doesn't grant the ability to
perform the attack
however in conjunction with this right
they can perform it
and if you look at that 2nd one
get changes that is
most likely that right
come on
sometimes it's hard to click on the edges
but
abuse info
if we want to run mimicaps on the box we could
but impact it has a DC sync tool as well
so we can just run that tool so let's go
1st
a new pain
you don't need this pain anymore
so we can do secrets dump dot pie
egotistical bank dot local slash SVC
learn mgr
at 1010 175
and let's copy the password
so
whoops we don't want that yet
essentially how secrets dump works
it's just secret dump
and then a username and then at the target
so egotessical dashbank dot local
that's domain SBC loan manager
that's the user
at 10 1010 one 75 which is the domain controller
paste the password in
and we can see
it doing a DC sync
and essentially what this attack is is
it's saying hey
domain controller I'm another domain controller
in order to join the domain we need to sync password
so send me all the hashes and stuff
so that's essentially what DC sync is
and that lets us get the administrator hash
and we can probably use this to do
a pass the hash attack so we can do
crack map exec dash U
administrator dash P or I think dash capital H for hash
so let's try this 1st
10 1010 one 75
and we can see
it says pound whenever it says pound
we should be able to do PS exact
so let's do the same thing
let's just go to a
secret stump command
erase that and do PS exec dot pi
and change it to be
administrator
have got pie twice
paste the hash
oh I copied pound
let's copy
this
L date that's my clipboard
run it
ah
the exact
pie H
let's see is there a special thing for a hash
dash ashes
question shares
so the format for dash hashes is
let's see
Len man hash NTLM hash
and
this is actually like that AAD3B thing
that's let's see
this
which is the landman hash of nothing
windows doesn't really use this anymore
and it's not part of the authentication
you can either authenticate with landman
which is disable nowadays or NTLM
and since the tool is asking for both
since it's not going to use landman
I just always have the habit of pacing the NTLM twice
so
with this we can now go to CD backslash
users administrator
if I can type
test stop
and
get the root dot text so
that'll be the box
I hope you guys enjoyed it
take care
and I'll see you all next week