what's going on YouTube
this is I'm doing sauna from hack the box
which is just a
windows box with a web server and active directory
and start on it
we've done plenty of 80 in the past
the videos that come to mine
a real active sizzle and forest
the thing that really sets this one apart
is you can't just use
RPC client or L DAP to dump all the users on the box
instead we can kind of
do a boolean logic to check if a user exist
through kirbros pre authentication
essentially you give it a username if
kirbros responds with
pre authentication required
you know that user exist on the box
so we're going to go through the website of the box
pull a bunch of names off the site
and then use a bit of them
magic to convert those names into possible usernames
pass it into a tool called curb route
to find some valid usernames
and then with those usernames
pass it to some impacket scripts to do some as
rep roasting to get a
password hash of an account pass it to hashcat
crack it log into the box
and then once you log into the box
privasking is simply running
blood hound and wind peas
combining the 2 outputs and you can DC sync
so it probably sounds a lot more complicated than it is
so let's just jump in
as always we want to start over
the n map so dash s C for default scripts
s V enumerate versions O a I'll put all formats
print the n map directory and we have to create it
create the n map directory
and then we can call it sauna
1010 175
always want to run and map with pseudo
and then I'm gonna add a dash V flag
so we can see open ports as it finds it
we see 80 is open which is going to be a web server
53 DNS a bunch of um like SMB RPC ports
I don't know exactly what 3268 is
um don't know what five ninety three
I think 06:36 is encrypted L DAP
we see kerbros down here
so based upon saying 4 45 which is SMB
so we know there's a windows box
53 DNS and 88 kurbrose
I'm guessing this is a windows domain controller
so the very 1st thing I want to do is probably
enumerate 4 or 4 or 5
and then we'll move on to port 80
so let's do
crack map exec SMB 1010
175 to see
everything about this
hurst we see the hurst name is going to be sana
the domain name is egotistical dashbank dot local
signing is set to true and smbv1 is disabled
so
let's do shares to see if we can enumerate any shares
and we get a status use a chess and delete in
we can try a blank username password
to see if this gets around that
sometimes it does sometimes it doesn't
and we see access denied so we can't
we could try other tools like SMB map
I think it's dash I 10 1010 one 75 dash U dash
P
dash H
run
this and we don't really get anything
so
good go and try a bunch of SMB tools